Inventory of the Benjamin Stoddert Ewell Papers 1784-1934
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Letters, 1784-1934. (Folder 1-19)
  - Letters: F-G, 1784-1934 (Folder 11)
    - Grisby (Hugh Blair), at Charlotte Court House, Virginia, to Benjamin S. Ewell, 15 November 1876. (Folder 11)
    - Gwynn (Walter), chief engineer, James River and Kanawha Company, at Richmond, to John Y. Mason, president, 18 February 1851. (Folder 11)
    - Gwynn (Walter), at Richmond, to B. S. Ewell, 17 March 1851. (Folder 11)
  - Letters: H, 1784-1934 (Folder 12)
    - Hall (J. Lesslie), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Mrs. Beverly Scott, at Ewell, James City County, Virginia, 7 February 1902. (Folder 12)
    - Ham (Lewis C.), at Richmond, to Col. B. S. Ewell, at Atlanta, Georgia, 1863. (Folder 12)
    - Hampden Sidney College, Board of Visitors, 21 August 1846. (Folder 12)
      Letter from F. N. Watkins, secretary, with resolutions of the board thanking Benjamin S. Ewell for his services as an instructor and officer of the college.
    - Hampden Sidney College, Board of Visitors, 2 August 1848. (Folder 12)
      Letter from F. N. Watkins, secretary, to Benjamin S. Ewell, notifying him of his election to the chair of mathematics.
    - Harvie (E. J.), War Records Office, at Washington, D.C., to Elizabeth Ewell Scott, at Ewell Station, Virginia, 21 February 1895. (Folder 12)
    - Haupt (William W.), at Philadelphia, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Buckland P.O., Prince William County, Virginia. Forwarded to Lexington, Rockbridge County, 14 August 1848. (Folder 12)
    - Haupt (William W.), at Belmont, Sumter County, Alabama, to Benjamin S. Ewell, William and Mary College, Virginia, 22 March 1849. (Folder 12)
    - Hawes (Katharine Reeth) and Mrs. Horace S. Hawes, of the South Atlantic Field Committee of the National Board of the Young Women's Christian Associations, at Richmond, Virginia, to Mrs. R. M. Crawford, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 18 January 1919. (Folder 12)
    - Hayden (Horace Edw.), at Wilkes-Barre, Pennsylvania, to Col. B. S. Ewell, February-March 1889., 2 items. (Folder 12)
      - Letter, 26 February 1889. (Folder 12)
      - Letter, 23 March 1889. (Folder 12)
    - Heth (Harry), acting Marshal-in-chief, Inauguration of the Jackson Statue, at Richmond, Virginia, to Col. Benjamin S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia. and James L. Kemper, Governor of Virginia, at Richmond, to Harry Heth.(On same sheet.), 22 October 1875 and 4 October 1875. (Folder 12)
    - Hobson (Annie J. W.), at Richmond, to Col. Ewell, 29 September 1877. (Folder 12)
    - Hoge ( ? ) to [ ? ]. (Folder 12)
    - Hoge (Addison), at Oxford, Mississippi, to Col. B. S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 18 May 1888. (Folder 12)
    - Hoge (Miss E. Lacy), at Richmond, to Elizabeth Ewell, daughter of Benjamin S. Ewell, 16 November 1865. (Folder 12)
    - Hoge (Mary R.), at Richmond, Virginia, to Elizabeth Ewell, daughter of Benjamin S. Ewell, August 1863-April 1864., 4 items. (Folder 12)
      - Letter, 24 August 1863. (Folder 12)
      - Letter, 26 November 1863. (Folder 12)
      - Letter, 21 March 1864. (Folder 12)
      - Letter, 7 April 1864. (Folder 12)
    - Hoge (Mary R.) to Elizabeth Ewell, 25 October 1864. (Folder 12)
    - Hoge (Mary R.) to Elizabeth Ewell, December 1864-October [?]., 2 items. (Folder 12)
      - Letter, 14 December 1864. (Folder 12)
      - Letter, 24 October [ ? ]. (Folder 12)
    - Hoge (Mary S.), at Oakley, probably to Elizabeth Ewell, daughter of Benjamin S. Ewell, No date. (Folder 12)
    - Hoge (Moses D.), at Baltimore, Maryland to Professor [ ? ] Dabney, 17 June 1854. (Folder 12)
    - Hoge (Moses D.), at Richmond, to B. S. Ewell, August 1865-March 1866., 3 items. (Folder 12)
      - Letter, 23 August 1865. (Folder 12)
      - Letter, 24 October 1865. (Folder 12)
      - Letter, 20 March 1866. (Folder 12)
    - Hoge (Moses D.), A. Z. Mollwaine, A. D. Dickinson, at Richmond, to B. S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 16 May 1866. (Folder 12)
    - Hoge (Moses D.), at Richmond, to B. S. Ewell, 20 December 1866. (Folder 12)
    - Hoge (Moses D.), at Baltimore, to Benjamin S. Ewell, 8 September 1867. (Folder 12)
    - Hoge (Moses D.), at Richmond, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 24 December 1885. (Folder 12)
    - Hoge (Susan), at Richmond, to Elizabeth Ewell, daughter of Benjamin S. Ewell., 3 items. (Folder 12)
      - Letter, 3 December 1863. (Folder 12)
      - Letter, 4 August 1865. (Folder 12)
      - Letter, An undated letter. (Folder 12)
    - Hoge (W. J.), at Baltimore, to Rev. William H. McGuffey, at the University of Virginia, 4 January 1854. (Folder 12)
    - Hopkins (W. P.), at Lawrence, Massachusetts, to Benjamin S. Ewell, 6 October 1885. (Folder 12)
    - Hough (M.), at Baltimore, to Elizabeth Ewell, daughter of Benjamin S. Ewell, 9 February 1859. (Folder 12)
    - Hough (M.), at Charlottesville, to Elizabeth Ewell, no date. (Folder 12)
    - Hubbard (David), at Kinlock, Alabama, to Rebecca Ewell, at Buckland, Prince William County, Virginia. R. Hubbard to Rebecca Ewell. (On same sheet.), 30 April 1849. (Folder 12)
    - Hubbard (David), at Kinlock, Lawrence County, Alabama, to Rebecca L. Ewell, at Buckland, Virginia, 3 January 1849. (Folder 12)
    - Hubbard (David), at Washington, to Rebecca L. Ewell, 23 January 1850. (Folder 12)
    - Hubbard (James L.), Nelson County, Virginia, to Benjamin S. Ewell, 7 January 1875. (Folder 12)
    - Hubbard (R.) to Elizabeth Ewell Scott, 20 April 1869. (Folder 12)
    - Hubbard (R.), at Chestnut Grove, to her sister, Mrs. Elizabeth Ewell, mother of Benjamin S. Ewell, at Buckland, Prince William County, Virginia Postmarked Kenlock, Alabama. Forwarded to Rebecca L. Ewell, at Washington, D.C. (Folder 12)
    - Hubbard (R.) to Rebecca Ewell., Three letters. (Folder 12)
    - Hubbard (R.) to Rebecca Lowndes Ewell, at Buckland, Prince William County, Virginia. Postmarked Kenlock, Alabama. (Folder 12)
    - Hubbard (R.) to Rebecca L. Ewell, at Buckland, Prince William County, Virginia. Postmarked Washington, D.C., Two letters. (Folder 12)
    - Hubbard (R.) to Rebecca L. Ewell, at Buckland, Prince William County, Virginia. Postmarked Kenlock, Alabama. (Folder 12)
    - Hubbard (R.) to Rebecca L. Ewell and William Stoddert, near Greenwich, Prince William County, Virginia. (Folder 12)
    - Hubbard (R.), at Kinlock, Lawrence County, Alabama, to Rebecca L. Ewell, at Buckland, Prince William County, Virginia. (Folder 12)
    - Hubbard (R.), at Washington, to Rebecca Ewell, undated., Two letters. (Folder 12)
    - Humphreys (A. A.), at Washington, to Benjamin Ewell, at Buckland, Prince William County, Virginia, 14 June 1849. (Folder 12)
    - Hutchison (Westwood), Commander Ewell Camp C. V., at Manassas, Virginia, to Bessie Scott Crawford, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 3 February 1914. (Folder 12)
  - Letters: I-K, 1784-1934 (Folder 13)
    - International Exhibition Company, at Philadelphia, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 2 April 1877. (Folder 13)
      An invitation to the International Exhibition at Philadelphia, 1877.
    - James (James Rufus), at Jackson Hospital, Richmond, Virginia, to Elizabeth Ewell, daughter of Benjamin S. Ewell, 1 May 1865. (Folder 13)
    - Jenkins (S.), at Adam's Run, South Carolina, to [Elizabeth Ewell?], 16 April 1866. (Folder 13)
    - Jenkins (S.), at Adam's Run, South Carolina, to Elizabeth Ewell, 10 June 1866. (Folder 13)
    - Jenkins (S.) to [ ? ]. (Folder 13)
    - Johns (J.), at George Town, to Professor Benjamin S. Ewell, at Buckland, Virginia, 4 September 1851. (Folder 13)
    - Johnson (Henry R.), at Honey Grove, Fannin County, Texas, to Col. B. S. Ewell, 16 June 1873. (Folder 13)
    - Johnson (M. C.), chairman, Trustees of Transylvania University, at Lexington, Kentucky, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Hampden Sidney College, Prince Edward Court House, Virginia, 31 January 1841. (Folder 13)
    - Johnston (General Joseph E.), 10 March 1863. (Folder 13)
      Invitation to a soiree dansante to be given in honor of General Joseph E. Johnston.
    - Johnston (J. E.), at Baltimore, to B. S. Ewell, 21 May 1868. (Folder 13)
    - Johnston (J. E.), at Richmond, to Col. Benjamin S. Ewell, 12 October 1868. (Folder 13)
    - Johnston (J. E.), at Hot Springs, Virginia, to Col. B. S. Ewell, 9 July 1870. (Folder 13)
    - Johnston (J. E.), at Savannah, Georgia, to Col. B. S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 11 April 1871. (Folder 13)
    - Johnston (J. E.), at Savannah, Georgia, to Col. B. S. Ewell, 20 September 1871. (Folder 13)
    - Johnston (J. E.), at Washington, D.C., to Col. B. S. Ewell, 28 June 1889. (Folder 13)
    - Johnston (J. E.), at Washington, to Col. B. S. Ewell, 19 July 1889. (Folder 13)
    - Jones (David), at New Castle, Delaware, to Benjamin S. Ewell, 26 May 1879. (Folder 13)
    - Kent (Demos), at Bladensburgh, Maryland, to B. S. Ewell, at West Point, New York, 31 December 1831. (Folder 13)
    - Keyes (E. D.), at West Point, New York, 11 April 1848. (Folder 13)
    - Kingman (Cordelia Bell), at Washington, to Rebecca Ewell, 3 September 1865. (Folder 13)
    - Knowlton (Miner), at West Point, New York, 8 November 1838. (Folder 13)
  - Letters: L-M, 1784-1934 (Folder 14)
    - Lamb (William), at Norfolk, to Elizabeth Ewell Scott, 18 July 1899. (Folder 14)
    - Lane (Robert W.), at Washington, to B. S. Ewell, 5 April 1848. (Folder 14)
    - Lawson (John W.), at Smithfield, Virginia, to Col. B. S. Ewell and T. M. Thompson, 24 November 1887. (Folder 14)
    - Lee (J. F.), at Washington, to Benjamin Ewell, at Buckland, Prince William County, Virginia. Forwarded to Williamsburg, Virginia, 25 June 1849. (Folder 14)
    - Lee (J. F.), at Washington, to Benjamin S. Ewell, 8 March 1855. (Folder 14)
    - Lee (J. F.), at Annapolis, to Col. Benjamin S. Ewell, 23 January 1868. (Folder 14)
    - Lewis (M. L.) to Rebecca Ewell, no date. (Folder 14)
    - Lossing (Benson J.), at Poughkeepsie, New York, to B. S. Ewell, at William and Mary College, Virginia, 15 November 1866. (Folder 14)
    - Lowndes (B. O.), at Blenheim[?], to B. Ewell, 19 May 1879. (Folder 14)
    - Lowndes (Charles, Jr.) to Francis Lowndes, Jr., at Georgetown, no date. (Folder 14)
    - Lowndes (F.), at Georgetown, to Rebecca Ewell, 20 February 1866. (Folder 14)
    - Lowndes (Lloyd), at Clarksburg, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, 10 November 1868. (Folder 14)
    - M[?] (Alice) to Lizzie [ ? ], no date. (Folder 14)
    - McCandlish (R.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Washington College, Lexington, Virginia. Forwarded to Buckland, Prince William County, 15 July 1848. (Folder 14)
    - McIlvain (John), at Maryland Heights, Maryland, to Elizabeth Ewell, daughter of Benjamin S. Ewell, no date. (Folder 14)
    - McIlvain (William), at York, Pennsylvania, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Buckland, Prince William County, Virginia, May 1839-June 1839., 2 items. (Folder 14)
      - Letter, 3 May 1839. (Folder 14)
      - Letter, 18 June 1839. (Folder 14)
    - McIlvain (William), at York, Pennsylvania, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Hampden Sidney College, Prince Edward County, Virginia, October 1839-August 1840., 5 items. (Folder 14)
      - Letter, 23 October 1839. (Folder 14)
      - Letter, 25 January 1840. (Folder 14)
      - Letter, 14 May 1840. (Folder 14)
      - Letter, 11 July 1840. (Folder 14)
      - Letter, 17 August 1840. (Folder 14)
    - McIlvain (William), at Washington, D.C., to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Hampden Sydney, Virginia, 4 March 1841. (Folder 14)
    - McIlvain (William), at York, Pennsylvania, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Prince Edward Post Office, Virginia, 12 June 1841. (Folder 14)
    - McIlvain (William), at York, Pennsylvania, to B. S. Ewell, at Hampden Sydney College, Prince Edward Court House, Virginia. William McIlvain to his daughter, Julia Ewell. (On same sheet.), 17 November 1841. (Folder 14)
    - McIlvain (William), at York, Pennsylvania, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Hampden Sydney College, Prince Edward Court House, Virginia, May 1842-July 1842., 2 items. (Folder 14)
      - Letter, 21 May 1842. (Folder 14)
      - Letter, 27 July 1842. (Folder 14)
    - McIlvain (William), at York, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Buckland P.O., Prince William County, Virginia, 20 October 1843. (Folder 14)
    - McIlvain (William), at York, Pennsylvania, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Prince Edward College [i.e., Hampden Sidney College], Virginia, 7 December 1843. (Folder 14)
    - McIlvain (William), at York, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Prince Edward Court House, Virginia, 30 July 1844. (Folder 14)
    - McIlvain (William), at York, to B. S. Ewell, 4 January 1845. (Folder 14)
    - McIlvain (William), at York, to Elizabeth Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia. William McIlvain to Julia Ewell. (On same sheet.), 20 January 1851. (Folder 14)
    - McIlvain (William), at York, to Elizabeth Ewell, 26 June 1854. (Folder 14)
    - McIlvain (William) to Benjamin S. Ewell, no date. (Folder 14)
    - McLane (Robert), at Washington, D.C., to John Tyler and the Board of Visitors of William and Mary College, Virginia, 5 April 1848. (Folder 14)
    - Magruder (G. A., Jr.), assistant aide-de-camp, at Headquarters, Half Way House, to Col. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 8 June 1861. (Folder 14)
    - Mahan (D. H.), at West Point, New York, to John Tazewell, D. H. Mahan, at West Point, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Lexington, Virginia (On same sheet.), 6 April 1848. (Folder 14)
    - Mahan (D. H.), at West Point, New York, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Lexington, Virginia, 17 April 1848. (Folder 14)
    - Mahan (D. H.), at West Point, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 8 February 1851. (Folder 14)
    - Maxwell (William) to George E. Dabney, at Richmond, no date. (Folder 14)
    - Meade (Edwin D.), at Boston, to Benjamin S. Ewell, 4 June [ ? ]. (Folder 14)
    - Meade (William), at Millwood, Clarke County, Virginia, to Professor Ewell, at William and Mary College, Williamsburg, Virginia, 18 March 1849. (Folder 14)
    - Mercer (C. F.), at Alexandria, to Mrs. Elizabeth Ewell, 30 May 1826. (Folder 14)
    - Mifflin (S. W.), at York, Pennsylvania, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Buckland P.O., Virginia. Forwarded to Prince Edward Court House, 10 October 1839. (Folder 14)
    - Mitchell (G.), at Annapolis, Maryland, to Doctor Thomas Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., 11 November 1806. (Folder 14)
    - Moncure (Henry W.), Henry Ludlam and Joshua Fry, at Richmond, to B. S. Ewell, at Prince Edward Court House, 4 March 1846. (Folder 14)
      Printed circular letter requesting aid for the family of John Hampden Pleasants who was killed in a duel.
    - Monroe (James), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Benjamin S. Ewell, 14 September 1870. (Folder 14)
    - Monroe (James), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Benjamin S. Ewell, 28 September 1870. (Folder 14)
    - Moore (E. S.), A. S. Brown, and A. L. Nelson, at Washington College, Lexington, Virginia, to B. S. Ewell, 22 September 1848. (Folder 14)
    - Munford (Maria) to Elizabeth S. Ewell, daughter of Benjamin S. Ewell, April 1859. (Folder 14)
    - Munford (Maria), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Bristoe [i.e., Bristow] Station, Prince William County, Virginia. Forwarded to Williamsburg, Virginia, 3 September 1859. (Folder 14)
    - Munford (Maria), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, 20 October 1859. (Folder 14)
    - Munford (Maria), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, October 1860., 2 items. (Folder 14)
      - Letter, 5 October 1860. (Folder 14)
      - Letter, 8 October 1860. (Folder 14)
    - Munford (Maria), at Richmond, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, 27 June 1866. (Folder 14)
    - Munford (Maria), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, 5 August 1867. (Folder 14)
    - Munford (Maria) to Elizabeth S. Ewell, undated., Three letters. (Folder 14)
    - Munford (Sallie), at Richmond, to Elizabeth Ewell, March-April 1862., 2 items. (Folder 14)
      - Letter, 27 March 1862.
      - Letter, 23 April 1862.
    - Munford (Sallie), at Dundee, Bedford County, Virginia, to Elizabeth Ewell, 22 May 1862. (Folder 14)
    - Munford (Sallie), at Richmond, to Elizabeth Ewell, 22 October 1862. (Folder 14)
    - Munford (Sallie), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth Ewell, 16 May 1865. (Folder 14)
    - Munford (Sallie), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth Ewell, at Richmond, Virginia, 30 May 1865. (Folder 14)
    - Munford (Sallie), at Madisonville, Charlotte County, to Elizabeth Ewell, no date. (Folder 14)
    - Munford (Sallie), at Tazewell Hall, Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth Ewell, no date. (Folder 14)
  - Letters: N-R, 1784-1934 (Folder 15)
    - Nelson (A. L.), at University of Virginia, to William J. Robertson, at Charlottesville, Virginia, 3 June 1854. (Folder 15)
    - Nelson (A. L.), at University of Virginia, to the Board of Visitors of the University of Virginia, 26 June 1854. (Folder 15)
      Letter giving his opinion of Benjamin S. Ewell as an instructor.
    - Nelson (A. L.), at Lexington, Virginia, to Col. Benjamin S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia. Forwarded to Ewell, Virginia, 25 May 1894. (Folder 15)
    - Nelson (Robert), at Shanghai, China, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 10 November 1873. (Folder 15)
    - Page (F. N.), at Shelby, Gloucester County, Virginia, to Professor Benjamin S. Ewell, 18 April 1849. (Folder 15)
    - Peachy (Archibald C.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Benjamin S. Ewell, 17 September 1894. (Folder 15)
    - Peck (William G.), at Columbian College, New York, to B. S. Ewell, 1 November 1880. (Folder 15)
    - Pemberton (J. C.), May 12-18, 1863. (Folder 15)
    - Pemberton (J. C.), 1 Oct - 14 December 1863. (Folder 15)
    - Perry (Maud Shirley), at Riverside, Connecticut, to [ ? ], 4 September 1894. (Folder 15)
    - Perry (William Stevens), at Geneva, New York, to Benjamin S. Ewell, 1 November 1870. (Folder 15)
    - Peyton (R. H.), at Augusta Arsenal, Georgia, to B. S. Ewell, at West Point, New York, 3 May 1835. (Folder 15)
    - Peyton (R. H.) to B. S. Ewell, at West Point, New York. Postmarked Augusta, Georgia, no date. (Folder 15)
    - Pinkney (E. H.) to Elizabeth S. Ewell, sister of Benjamin S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C. Postmarked Bladensburg, Maryland, 7 February 1868. (Folder 15)
    - Pinkney (W.) to Francis Lowndes, 1 May 1850. (Folder 15)
    - Pinkney (W.) to Gen. Benjamin Ewell, 22 September 1879. (Folder 15)
    - Plumer (William S.), at Baltimore, Maryland, to Hon. John Tyler and Robert G. Scott, 10 April 1848. (Folder 15)
    - Plumer (William S.), at Philadelphia, to the Visitors of the University of Virginia, 15 June 1854. (Folder 15)
      Recommending Benjamin S. Ewell for a professorship.
    - Prout (A. L.), Rebecca L. Ewell, at Buckland, Prince William County, Virginia, August-December 1847., 3 items. (Folder 15)
      - Letter, 8 August 1847. (Folder 15)
      - Letter, 20 December 1847. (Folder 15)
      - Letter, 26 December 1847. (Folder 15)
    - Prout (A. L.), at Ewells, James City County, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, sister of Benjamin S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., 12 May 1874. (Folder 15)
    - Prout (Nannie S.), at Washington, to her cousin [ ? ], 8 March 1851. (Folder 15)
    - Randolph (Theo. F.), at White Sulphur Springs, to Col. Benjamin S. Ewell, 23 July 1874. (Folder 15)
    - Rasin (R. W.), to Benjamin S. Ewell, 23 August 1866. (Folder 15)
    - Reid (Samuel McD.), at Lexington, Virginia, to Benjamin S. Ewell, at Hampden Sydney College, Prince Edward Court House, Virginia, 14 March 1846. (Folder 15)
    - Reynolds (William, Jr.), at Baltimore, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, daughter of Benjamin S. Ewell, at Richmond, 23 June 1865. (Folder 15)
    - Reynolds (William, Jr.), at Baltimore, to Elizabeth S. E. Scott, at Farmville, Prince Edward County, Virginia, 2 January 1868. (Folder 15)
    - Richards (J. H.), at Georgetown College, West Washington, D.C., to Gen. Benjamin S. Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia. Forwarded to Ewell, James City County, 22 November 1891. (Folder 15)
    - Richardson (Charles F.), at New York, to Col. Benjamin S. Ewell, 9 March 1877. (Folder 15)
    - Richardson (Charles F.), at Hanover, New Hampshire, to Col. Benjamin S. Ewell, 22 January 1889. (Folder 15)
    - Ridgely (Samuel Chase), at West Point, New York, to M. Knowlton, 9 November 1838. (Folder 15)
    - Round (George C.), at Manassas, Prince William County, Virginia, to Professor Ewell, at Williamsburg, Virginia, 2 December 1884. (Folder 15)
    - Round (George C.), at Belle Air, Prince William County, Virginia, to President Ewell, 26 June 1885. (Folder 15)
    - Round (George C.), at Belle Air, Prince William County, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Ewell, sister of Benjamin S. Ewell, 24 September 1885. (Folder 15)
  - Letters: S, 1784-1934 (Folder 16-17)
    - S[tringfellow](H. M.), at Jamestown, Virginia, to Elizabeth Ewell, daughter of Benjamin S. Ewell, no date. (Folder 16)
    - S [ ? ] (M. M.), at Hampden Sidney, to Elizabeth Ewell, no date. (Folder 16)
    - Saunders (Page), at Fincastle, Botetourt County, Virginia, to Elizabeth Ewell, daughter of Benjamin S. Ewell, 4 September 1857. (Folder 16)
    - Saunders (Page), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth Ewell, 4 September 1859. (Folder 16)
    - Saunders (Page), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth Ewell, 3 March 1862. (Folder 16)
    - Saunders (Page) to Elizabeth Ewell, at Hampden Sidney College, Virginia, July 1862. (Folder 16)
    - Saunders (Page) to Elizabeth Ewell, (May 1862-post 1865.), Five undated letters. (Folder 16)
    - Saunders (Page), at Chatham, to Elizabeth Ewell, at Spring Hill, Maury County, Tennessee, (May 1862-post 1865.) (Folder 16)
    - Saunders (Page), at the "Rectory," Pittsylvania Court House, Virginia, to Elizabeth Ewell, (May 1862-post 1865.), Four undated letters. (Folder 16)
    - Saunders (Page), at Pittsylvania Court House, to Elizabeth Ewell, no date. (May 1862-post 1865.) (Folder 16)
    - Saunders (Page), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth Ewell, (May 1862-post 1865.), Two undated letters. (Folder 16)
    - Saunders (Page), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Elizabeth S. Scott, at Prince Edward Court House, Virginia, no date. (May 1862-post 1865.) (Folder 16)
    - Saunders (Page) to [ ? ]. (Folder 16)
    - Saunders (Robert) to Mrs. Elizabeth Ewell, mother of Benjamin S. Ewell, 7 June 1854. (Folder 16)
    - Saunders (Robert), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Andrew Stevenson, 14 June 1854. (Folder 16)
    - Saunders (Robert), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Henry A. Wise, 14 June 1854. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (Beverly) to Elizabeth Ewell Scott, December 1882- October 1901., 2 items. (Folder 16)
      - Letter, 5 December 1882. (Folder 16)
      - Letter, 23 October 1901. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (Beverly) to Elizabeth Scott, no date. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (Beverly) to Elizabeth S. E. Scott, at Richmond, Virginia, no date. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (Elizabeth L.), at Ewell, Virginia, to her aunt, Elizabeth S. Ewell, sister of Benjamin S. Ewell, 3 May 1893. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (Elizabeth L.) to her mother, Mrs. Beverly S. Scott, [i.e., Elizabeth Ewell Scott], at Ewell, James City County, Virginia, 29 January 1891. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (Elizabeth L.) to her mother, Mrs. Beverly S. Scott, 30 December 1896. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (Elizabeth L.) to Mrs. Beverly S. Scott, 7 January 1897. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (Elizabeth) to Mrs. Beverly Scott, at Ewell, James City County, Virginia, 25 January 1897. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (Elizabeth), at Branford, Connecticut, to her father, Beverly S. Scott, at Ewell, Virginia, 19 May 1901. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (Elizabeth L.), at Williamsburg, Virginia, to the editor of the News Leader, at Richmond, Virginia, 5 February 1909. (Folder 16)
    - Scott (Elizabeth L.) to Mrs. Beverly S. Scott (Folder 16)
    - Scott (Elizabeth L.) to Mrs. Beverly Scott, at Ewells, James City County, Virginia, no date. (Folder 16)